#### BENEDICTO G. DE LEON JR.

# Blk 105 Jurong East Street 13, #11-226 Singapore 600105 +65 9062 3736

benedicto.gualda.deleon@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

Benedicto De Leon Jr. has **11 years and 1 month** of software development experience with **2 Java certifications**. He started working as PHP Developer in 2006 and shifted to Java development in 2007. He was involved in different Java projects from different companies. He worked with people from different countries like USA, Germany, Russia, UK, Brazil, India, and Singapore.

He was involved in the development and support of projects in Banking Industry (Deutsche Bank, East West Bank, United Overseas Bank), Retail Industry (Oracle Retail), and Telecommunications Industry (Sprint).

His primary skill is Java. His secondary skills are Oracle (PL/SQL) and Unix/Linux.

### **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Completed production implementation of United Overseas Bank's Anti-Money Laundering system (as DL Resources Contractor for United Overseas Bank).
- Completed a 1-year development project in Sprint Telco using Agile Scrum methodology. Received recognition from the client after completing the project (as IBM Contractor for Sprint).
- Involved in Level 2 Production support for Sprint Telco for 6 months (as IBM Contractor for Sprint).
- Involved in the development of Child Support System in Wisconsin, USA. (as ACS of the Philippines Contractor for US Government).
- Converted C++ codes to Java (as employee of National Collection Office, Inc.)
- Involved in I18N (Internationalization) project in Oracle Retail. (as Accenture Contractor for Oracle)
- Involved in the development of Advanced Inventory Planning (AIP) using Java, Oracle PL/SQL, and UNIX. (as Accenture Contractor for Oracle)
- Involved in support and maintenance of Credit Risk Management System in Deutsche Bank (as Accenture Contractor for Deutsche Bank).
- Involved in the development of e-Forms for CRM project using Java Web Services, XML, XSLT, Javascript, and Oracle PL/SQL (as Rivereo Contractor for Lagan, Inc.)
- Completed an Automated Credit Management System (Housing Loan Web Application) of East West Banking Corporation in the Philippines. (as employee of East West Banking Corporation).

#### **EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE**

#### Analyst/Programmer, DL Resources Pte Ltd.

July 2015 - present

- Involved in deploying United Overseas Bank's Anti-Money Laundering (AML) application.
  This AML application was developed by vendor (BAE Detica) and it focuses on screening
  UOB customer names against watch list data (world-check) from Thomson Reuters. The
  application will generate alert when a customer name matches with the name of one or
  more watch lists.
- Created SQL queries for UOB's AML Watch List Reports and fixed Customer Due Diligence (CDD) Reports.
- Created shell scripts and DB scripts for moving table and index tablespace in Oracle.
- Created anonymous PL/SQL block for updating millions of records using BULK COLLECT.
- Updated Oracle packages and views in AML projects.
- Created and updated Ctrl M jobs flow for UOB AML.

- Created/modified Java classes for Report Utilities.
- Reviewed SQL/shell script source codes of my teammates before deploying to UAT environment.
- Worked with UOB AML users during UAT phase and get UAT signoff from them.
- As member of Quarterly Release Team for AML, I worked with BAE Detica (vendor for AML application product) to make sure that vendor delivers the change requests as expected by UOB AML users.
- Tested the AML changes delivered by BAE Detica.
- Skills: IBM Rational ClearCase, IBM Rational ClearQuest, Aldon, Control-M, Unix, Weblogic, Oracle PL/SQL, SQL Developer, Java, Eclipse IDE.

## Senior Consultant, IBM Solutions Delivery Inc.

### Mar 2012 - June 2015

- Involved in the development and maintenance of Sprint Commissions Web Portal applications using Java, Servlets, and JSPs.
- Involved in the development and maintenance of Forecasting Tool Web Application for IBM.
- Created SQL scripts for creating and altering table for Sprint Commissions web application projects.
- Created SQL scripts for updating Oracle tables, Views, stored functions, stored procedures, packages, and triggers.
- Involved in Sprint Commissions Production Support. As part of Production Support team, I monitored running Control-M jobs.
- Attended daily calls with the client for providing updates to my tasks.
- Skills: **Agile Scrum**, Java, Servlets, JSP, EJB, Spring, JSON, jQuery, Javascript, AJAX, CSS, Oracle PL/SQL, Unix, JUnit, Toad, SQL Developer, WebLogic, JBoss, Eclipse IDE, MyEclipse IDE, SVN, Synergy, Control-M, Redmine, SM7

## Sr. Software Engineer, ACS of the Philippines, a Xerox company Aug 2011 – Mar 2012

- Involved in the development and maintenance of Child Support System for Wisconsin, USA.
- Created SQL scripts for updating Oracle stored functions.
- · Attended weekly calls with the client.
- Skills: Java, Servlets, JSP, Struts, Spring, Oracle PL/SQL, JBoss, Eclipse IDE, Perforce version control, Bugzilla

## **Programmer Analyst, NCO Financial Systems Inc.**

Jan 2011 - Aug 2011

- Involved in the development and maintenance of Collection Resource System.
- Converted C++ codes to Java codes.
- Modified UNIX shell scripts to run C++ programs.
- Used UNIX commands to build and deploy application.
- Attended weekly calls with the client.
- Skills: Java, Spring, C++,Unix Shell Script, JUnit, Maven, Checkstyle, Flat file Database, Tomcat, Eclipse IDE, StarTeam version control

## **Software Engineer, Accenture Inc.**

## Sep 2008 – Jan 2011

- Involved in the development and maintenance of Oracle Retail's Advanced Inventory Planning system.
- Involved in the development and maintenance of Deutsche Bank's Credit Risk Management system.
- Modified Oracle packages.
- Created SQL scripts for creating and altering Oracle tables.
- Created SQL scripts for updating stored procedures and functions.
- Built SQL queries (with INNER joins, OUTER joins, and subqueries) that are used when running UNIX batch programs.
- Monitored SQL performance using TKPROF and EXPLAIN PLAN.
- Modified UNIX shell scripts and XML files for running batch programs.

- Used Java1.4, Java1.5, and Java1.6 for maintaining different kinds of Oracle Retail applications.
- Attended daily calls with the client.
- Skills: Java, EJB, Struts, Spring, Unix Shell Script, Oracle PL/SQL, Tomcat, WebLogic, Oracle Application Server (OAS), XML, Ant, jQuery, javascript, Linux, JIRA, Bugzilla, HPQC, Hudson, CSS, Toad, JUnit, Maven, SQL Developer, Eclipse IDE, WinCVS, and CVS

## Software Engineer, Rivereo Inc.

Oct 2007 - Sep 2008

- Developed e-forms for CRM project using Java Web Services (SOAP-based).
- Modified Oracle PL/SQL and MS SQL codes.
- · Attended daily calls with the client.
- Skills: Java, Java Web Services, Oracle PL/SQL, MS SQL, Tomcat, XML, XSLT, Java Web Service, SoapUI, Javascript, CSS, SQL Developer, Eclipse IDE, SVN

## **Programmer, East West Banking Corporation**

Jun 2006 - Oct 2007

- Completed Two Way SMS web application project.
- Completed Automated Credit Management System for Housing Loans project.
- Completed E-mail broadcasting facility project.
- Completed Reports for Loans project.
- Completed Attendance System.
- Skills: PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle SQL, MS SQL, Apache Web Server, Javascript, AJAX, HTML, CSS, Ubuntu Linux, SQL Developer, Eclipse IDE

## **JAVA CERTIFICATIONS:**

Oracle Certified Professional Java SE 6 Programmer

Effective: March 4, 2011

Oracle Certified Professional Java EE 5 Web Component Developer

Effective: September 1, 2014

### **EDUCATION**

BS Computer Science Pangasinan State University Lingayen, Pangasinan, Philippines 2002-2006